Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Course Bulletins MC.286
New York University Archives
- Silver School of Social Work (RG 34), 1960-ongoing
  - Silver School of Social Work Master of Social Work, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the Master of Social Work at the Silver School, covering degree pathways, curriculum, course descriptions, non-matriculated and online options, study abroad options, and application information. The degree pathways include course sequences for part-time and full-time options for the Master's program, as well as dual degree options. The curriculum consists of a Generalist Practice level followed by a Specialized Practice level and course descriptions in these practices.
  - Silver School of Social Work Global Opportunities, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of Social Work classes offered at NYU study abroad location, including course descriptions, with a specific focus on the Shanghai-New York MSW program.
  - Silver School of Social Work Bachelor of Science, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the Bachelor of Science at the Silver School, covering curriculum, student experience, admissions, and an FAQ. The curriculum pages cover the course of study required for the major, dual major and minors, and study abroad.
  - Silver School of Social Work Doctorate in Clinical Social Work, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the Doctorate in Clinical Social Work at the Silver School, covering curriculum, course sequence, faculty, course descriptions, student and alumni accomplishments, and application information.
  - Silver School of Social Work Doctor of Philosophy, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the Doctor of Philosophy at the Silver School, covering curriculum, faculty, research, teaching experience, their lecture series, and student success stories. The website also covers the program requirements, including course descriptions of the social work core classes, advanced methodological/statistical courses, and substantive area of expertise courses, as well information on career preparation, the research practicum, qualifying exam, and dissertation.
  - Silver School of Social Work NYU Silver Experience, February-March 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the viewbook for the Silver School of Social Work for the Masters of Social Work degree.
- Tisch School of the Arts (RG 35), 1986-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1966-1984 (Box 161)
  - Bulletins, 1983-1992 (Box 162)
  - Bulletins, 1991-2003 (Box 163)
  - Bulletins, 2003-2013 (Box 164)
  - Bulletins (PDFs), 2009-2011, 2013-2015 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin, April 2014-May 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    The Tisch School of the Arts offers the B.A., B.F.A., M.F.A., M.P.S., M.A. (moving image archiving and preservation), and, through the Graduate School of Arts and Science, the M.A. (performance studies or cinema studies) and Ph.D degrees. Departments and programs offering professional training are acting, dance, design, drama, performance studies, film and television, cinema studies, photography and imaging, dramatic writing, musical theatre writing, recorded music, and interactive telecommunications.
  - Tisch School of the Arts: A Troubleshooter's Guide to Tisch and New York University (for Parents!), May-September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of a guide for parent's of Tisch students on housing, health, financial aid, academic issues, and social adjustment.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook, May-October 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook for 2015-2016.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Academic Integrity Policy, May-October 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Tisch School of the Arts Academic Integrity Policy.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin 2015-2017, May 2016-April 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Tisch School of the Arts bulletin for 2015-2017.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Student Affairs, May 2016-March 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website featuring information for students in Tisch. Includes information on academic services, student life, career development, financial aid, international students, parents, new student orientation, graduation, forms, tuition, housing, and staff.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook, May 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Policies and procedures handbook for the Tisch School of the Arts, which includes information about health and immunizations, registration and enrollment, discipline, harassment, grievance procedures, academic policies and procedures, and other student services.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook, May 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    PDFs for the Policies and Procedures Handbook, starting in 2015. The handbook covers matters such as academic standards, grading policies, registration regulations, and degree requirements.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin, May 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Landing page linking to a PDF of the Tisch Bulletin. Links to PDFs of bulletins from 2015-2017, 2017-2019, and 2019-2021.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Bulletin 2017-2019, November 2017-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Tisch School of the Arts course Bulletin for 2017-2019, which includes a faculty directory, academic calendar, administrative information about Tisch, descriptions of each department in the Institute of Performing Arts and the Maurice Kanbar Institute of Film and Television, and course listings by degree program.
  - Tisch School of the Arts Policies and Procedures Handbook 2019-2020, October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
- Gallatin School of Individualized Study (RG 36), 1981-2012, April 2014-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1981-1998 (Box 165)
  - Bulletins, 1998-2005 (Box 166)
  - Bulletins, 2006-2010 (Box 167)
  - Bulletins (PDFs), 2009-2012; cuid17996 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Gallatin School of Individual Study Bulletin, April 2014-June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    This page houses the Bulletin for New York University's Gallatin School of Individualized Study, with information about the structure and goals of individualized study programs, degree requirements, the IAPC essay, and the colloquium requirement for undergraduate students, as well as course offerings, study abroad opportunities, admissions, and financial aid resources. The page also details core courses and independent study components for individualized Master of Arts programs through Gallatin, and lists student resources and faculty profiles.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Course Directory, October 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Directory of courses and their descriptions offered at Gallatin. Courses are categorized by term, instruction mode, requirement, credit units, days and times offered, instructor, and course type.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Graduate Academics, October 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website detailing the components of graduate education at Gallatin. The website includes information degree requirements, the curriculum for enrollees before and after summer 2013, the master's thesis, graduate student community, and financial aid. The website details the core courses, elective courses, independent study, tutorials, internships, private lessons, advising, courses outside of NYU, and other NYU courses.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Undergraduate Academics, October 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website detailing the components of undergraduate education at Gallatin. The website includes the structure of the four-year program, degree requirements, study in other schools at NYU, global study, civic engagements, other learning opportunities, and student-directed learning. The website contains a listing of first-year program course descriptions, interdisciplinary seminars course descriptions, advanced writing course descriptions, arts workshops course descriptions, and degree requirements, plan for the concentration, and the practicum.
  - Gallatin School of Individualized Study Course Catalog, July 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  - Gallatin Fall 2022 Course Directory, October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
    Directory of courses and their descriptions offered at Gallatin for Fall 2022. Courses are categorized by term, instruction mode, requirement, credit units, days and times offered, instructor, and course type.
- Prison Education Program (RG 36.4), October 2021-ongoing
  - Prison Education Program Faculty and Courses, October 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website containing a faculty list and an overview of the curriculum and example courses in the Associate's Degree Program in Liberal Studies at Willkill Correctional Facility.
- Deutsches Haus (RG 37.3), 1977-1995
  - German language courses, 1977, 1981-1982, 1987-1992, 1995 (Box 168)
- Center for International Studies (RG 37.5), 1965-1971
  - Bulletins, 1965-1971 (Box 169)
- Institute for Hebrew and Judaic Studies (RG 37.8), 1963-1972
  - Bulletins, 1963-1972 (Box 170)
- Center for Near Eastern Studies (RG 37.14), 1987-1990
  - Bulletins, 1987-1990 (Box 170)
- Nassau College-Hofstra Memorial (RG 37.32), 1934-1939
  - Bulletins, 1934-1939 (Box 171)
- Center for Urban Science and Progress (RG 37.52), July 2017-ongoing
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Course Catalogue, July-November 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions for graduate courses at the Center for Urban Science and Progress (CUSP), including non-credit required courses, required core courses, and CUSP electives.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Master of Science Curriculum, August 2018-October 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the master of science curriculum at CUSP. The webpage includes preparatory resources, core course descriptions, electives descriptions, capstone projects, and student immersions.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics, March 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website detailing the Master of Science at the Center for Urban Science and Progress. Includes an overview of the program, curriculum, admissions requirements, tuition and financial aid, application guide, and admissions FAQ.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Master of Science Curriculum, June 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Online Advanced Certificate, October 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    This website contains course descriptions for the Advanced Certificate in Applied Urban Science and Informatics.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress BS in Sustainable Urban Environments & MS in Applied Urban Science and Progress, October 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website detailing the five year combined NYU Tandon School of Engineering's Bachelor of Science in Sustainable Urban Environments and NYU CUSP's Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics. Website includes the curriculum and application requirements.
  - Center for Urban Science and Progress Course Catalog, November 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Google document of required core classes and electives for the Master's program at the Center for Urban Science and Progress.
- Center for Data Science (RG 37.55), July 2014-ongoing
  - Center for Data Science Master of Science in Data Science, July 2014-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website detailing the curriculum and courses for the MS in Data Science. Website redirects to the homepage for the Center for Data Science in 2019.
  - Center for Data Science MS in Data Science Curriculum, September 2016-April 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Curriculum tracks for the MS in Data Science. Includes 4 semester and 3 semester options, required courses, and pre-approved elective courses.
  - Center for Data Science Required Courses, September 2016-April 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Listing of required courses and the order they should be taken in for the MS in Data Science.
  - Center for Data Science Pre-Approved Elective Courses, September 2016-April 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Listing of all electives approved for Data Science graduate students organized by discipline or domain.
  - Center for Data Science PhD in Data Science, April 2017-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the PhD in Data Science, with links to the study areas and faculty, curriculum, admission requirements, an FAQ, the medical school track, and the National Science Foundation Research Traineeship Future program.
  - Center for Data Science MS in Data Science Curriculum, November 2017-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Degree requirements for the MS in Data Science. Includes a listing of required courses, pre-approved elective information, course plans, data science track, bata science big data track, data science mathematics and data track, data science natural language processing track, data science physics track, data science biology track, and data science biomedical information track. In 2020, the URL redirects to the Center for Data Science homepage.
  - Graduate School of Arts & Science, Master of Science in Data Science, May 2018-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    This page lists the degree requirements for the Master of Science program at New York University's Center for Data Science, including required core courses and links to information about elective requirements, and information about the Master's' capstone project.
  - Center for Data Science Undergraduate Program, October 2019-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the Center for Data Science's undergraduate program. Includes information on the major and minors in data science, course listings, and an FAQ.
  - Center for Data Science PhD in Data Science, October 2019-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the Center for Data Science's PhD in Data Science. Includes details on the curriculum, admission requirements, faculty, and an FAQ. It also includes information on data science areas of concentration, specifically machine learning and perception, science and applications, theory, data management, and healthcare.
  - Center for Data Science MS in Data Science Curriculum, October 2019-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    This page lists courses offered by the MS Data Science program as well as out of approved out-of-department course offerings, and a sample 4 semester degree map/course plan. The page features links to individual class sites, as well as other pages with information about the NYU Center for Data Science.
  - Center for Data Science MS in Data Science Curriculum, March-June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Degree requirements for the MS in Data Science. Includes a listing of required courses, pre-approved elective information, course plans, data science track, data science big data track, data science mathematics and data track, data science natural language processing track, data science physics track, data science biology track, and data science biomedical information track. In 2020, the URL redirects to the Center for Data Science homepage.
  - Center for Data Science Undergraduate Courses, March 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Undergraduate courses offered at the Center for Data Science, including the Data Science for Everyone, Introduction to Data Science, Causal Inference, Responsible Data Science, and Advanced Topics in Data Science class descriptions.
  - Center for Data Science Undergraduate Program, March 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the undergraduate data science program. Includes information on the major and minor programs, joint major programs, courses offered, remote learning experiences in data science, and an FAQ on the program.
  - Center for Data Science PhD in Data Science Curriculum, March 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Curriculum for the PhD in Data Science. It includes the degree requirements, required course descriptions, elective courses, teaching requirement, comprehensive exam, depth qualifying exam, dissertation information, and an example course sequence.
  - Center for Data Science Course Offerings, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Listing of courses offered at the Center for Data Science. Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the website focuses on hybrid model of in-person and remote teaching for all course offerings.
  - Center for Data Science Fall 2021 Courses, July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Tandon School of Engineering (RG 48), 1981-ongoing
  Includes Polytechnic Institute of New York materials.
  - Bulletins, 2009-2011 (Box 171)
  - Bulletins (PDFs), 1981-1990, 1992-1995, 1999-2016; cuid17997 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Polytechnic Undergraduate and Graduate Bulletin (with addenda), May 2014-August 2018 (Box Electronic Records)
    The New York University Polytechnic School of Engineering bulletin/catalog is an official publication of NYU. It provides information about academic programs and a summary of Institute policies and procedures and selected activities and services. Information concerning admission, academic regulations and requirements, student services, academic offerings and a listing of administrative officers and faculty are included. Every effort has been made to publish a complete and accurate catalog. However, requirements, deadlines, tuition, fees, curricula, courses and staffing are subject to change at any time without advance notice or obligation. Some course descriptions may vary from actual course content because of advancements in the discipline, emphasis of individual instructors or decisions of the faculty to change the scope or content of the course. NYU Polytechnic School of Engineering is a comprehensive school of engineering, applied sciences, technology and research, and is rooted in a 158-year tradition of invention, innovation and entrepreneurship. The institution, founded in 1854, is the nation's second-oldest private engineering school. In addition to its main campus in New York City at MetroTech Center in downtown Brooklyn, it also offers programs at sites throughout the region, around the globe and remotely through online learning. The NYU School of Engineering is an integral part of NYU Abu Dhabi, NYU Shanghai, and the NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress (CUSP) in downtown Brooklyn.
  - Tandon School of Engineering Undergraduate and Graduate Bulletin, April 2015-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Tandon (formerly the Polytechnic School of Engineering) bulletins for 2014-2016, 2016-2018, 2018-2020, and 2020-2022. The bulletins includes graduate and undergraduate academic requirements and policies; academic department and degree and program information; lists of academic programs and curricula; and course descriptions. Also includes PDFs of bulletins dating back to 1981.
  - Polytechnic Institute of NYU Undergraduate and Graduate Catalog, April 2017-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the NYU Poly undergraduate and graduate catalog for 2011-2013.
- NYU Abu Dhabi (RG 49), 2015-ongoing
  - Bulletin (PDF), 2015-2016 (Box Electronic Records)
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Primary and Secondary Educational Engagement, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    The Office of Primary and Secondary Educational Engagement builds bridges between K-12 and higher education. The webpage contains information on the faculty speakers bureau and the activities and events of the Office.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin 2015-2016, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin for 2015-2016.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Academics, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website featuring information on NYUAD's academic divisions: Arts and Humanities, Engineering, Science, and Social Science.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Undergraduate Courses, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Full listing of undergraduate courses offered at NYU Abu Dhabi for Fall 2015 to Spring 2017.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Scholars Program Course Descriptions, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Descriptions for the courses in the program: U.S. Supreme Court's Treatment of the Relationship Between Church and State, US Foreign Policy, What Makes a Great Leader?, Public Speaking & Public Presentations, and Critical Thinking and Persuasive Writing.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Summer Academy Curriculum, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website for NYUAD's summer academy curriculum which included instruction in Critical Thinking and Writing, Mathematical Reasoning for the Sciences, Standardized Test Preparation, and Leadership Development and Public Speaking.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin 2016-17, September 2016-November 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin for 2016-2017.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Executive Education, September 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    The page contains information about NYU Abu Dhabi's executive education program, with an overview page and subpages on Custom Programs and Case Studies.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, November 2017-August 2018 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the NYU Abu Dhabi undergraduate bulletin for 2017-2018.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Graduate Global PhD Student Fellowships, November 2017-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website containing information on the PhD fellowship programs offered at NYU Abu Dhabi, including Art and Media, Biology, Chemical Engineering, Chemistry, Civil Engineering, Computer Science, Economics, Electrical Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, Psychology, Physics, and Transportation Planning and Engineering.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Undergraduate Core Curriculum, April 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Abu Dhabi Undergraduate Core Curriculum consists of two Core Colloquia, each of which addresses a significant global challenge from multidisciplinary perspectives, and four Core Competency Courses, one each in the four categories: Arts, Design, and Technology; Cultural Exploration and Analysis; Data and Discovery; and Structures of Thought and Society. Includes a PDF with the course descriptions.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin, February-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the NYU Abu Dhabi undergraduate bulletin for 2018-2019.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin 2019-2020, October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the 2019-2020 course bulletin for NYU Abu Dhabi including a mission statement, academic calendar, core curriculum, and programs at a glance, accreditation, degree requirements, and admissions for the NYUAD campus as well as departmental/program descriptions and individual course listings.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletins, October 2019-June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Webpage containing pdfs to the current and previous NYU Abu Dhabi bulletins, dating back to 2013.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Core Curriculum User Guide, 2019-2020, October 2019-June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF for NYU Abu Dhabi's core curriculum. It includes the mission statement for NYUAD and a description of the NYUAD Core, which consists of two Core Colloquia, each of which addresses a significant global challenge from multidisciplinary perspectives, and four Core Competency Courses, one each in the four categories: Arts, Design, and Technology; Cultural Explorations and Analysis; Data and Discovery; and Structures of Thought and Society. It also describes other core classes, including the first year writing seminar, quantitative reasoning, experimental inquiry, and Islamic studies.
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin 2020-2021, March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the NYU Abu Dhabi Bulletin for 2020-2021.